JAKE MILLER

Minneapolis, MN

jake-miller@hotmail.com, (651) 356-4981, https://jmiller-io.github.io/

SUMMARY

Engineering solutions for technical challenges since 2009. I discovered my love for software development during my time as an IT Systems Engineer, when it became clear that the more architectural aspects of technology were the strengths I wanted to develop the most. Taking ideas and turning them into functional, elegant applications is my mission.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer / IT Manager, Yeti Cycles, Denver/Minneapolis, 1/2019 – current

- Improved Product Engineering department's research, development and prototype product testing procedures by architecting a product development testing full stack web application
- Consumed external API to create a multi-country sales order tax calculation system, resulting in a streamlined sales order entry procedure for the Sales department and improved accuracy for cash flow reporting for the Finance department
- Developed Progressive Web App to assist customers with Yeti Cycle's product configuration, resulting in greater satisfaction and experience with the Yeti Cycles brand https://shocksetup.yeticycles.com
- Designed demo event management software for market research and prospective customer data collection to support Marketing initiatives that integrates with the Salesforce cloud, increasing sales and customer base
- Architected warehouse product inventory software used internally for sales/release and is consumed by the Yeti e-commerce platform, feeding product information to the B2C and B2B websites
- Explored and implemented innovative software solutions that add to the Yeti customer and partner experience
- Partnered with external developers for website and integration changes with Yeti's ERP system and custom built internally used web apps and APIs

Full Stack Developer / Technology Coordinator, Yeti Cycles, Denver, 6/2017 – 1/2019

- Supported legacy internally used full stack web applications
- Built and maintained web-based application to track technological assets from purchase to disposal and established asset management practices
- Manage the development and maintenance of documentation including software design, departmental policies, procedures, disaster recovery plans, and technical reports as it relates to IT Operations.
- Provides end-user communication for service outages, system upgrades, service improvements, service implementation, and service retirements.
- Develops standards for workstations, mobile devices, printers, servers and other devices.
- Researches, evaluates, recommends and implements new technologies to meet business requirements and contributes to long-range planning for systems evolution.

Technical Engineer | Windows Operations, CBS, Hollywood 7/2016 – 10/2016

- Assists vendors and internal departments with Windows server hosted service migrations and upgrades
- Ensures security policy compliance for the Windows environment by performing Operating System patching and application modernizations
- Maintains infrastructure equipment inventory and manages hardware lifecycle
- Performs data center management, including cable organization and hardware installation
- Provides troubleshooting and advanced analysis of requests within the Windows 2000 2012
 R2 environment

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript/ES6

VueJS/Vuetify

NodeJS

Express

SQL

MongoDB

HTML

CSS

RESTful APIs

Git/GitHub

OAuth

AWS Storage (S3, Glacier)

Template Engines

PowerShell

App-V

Enterprise Microsoft Technologies

VMware

Windows Server 2000-2019

Azure AD

Windows Systems Administrator, American Public Media Group, LA, 1/2013 – 9/2016

- Architects and manages the Active Directory environment for a multi-site hierarchy
- Assists in the architectural development and deployment of new installations and solutions in an ever-expanding VMware environment within a continuous improvement organization
- Automates administrative tasks in AD, Office 365, Exchange Online and VMware with the use of PowerShell and PowerCLI
- Designs and implements software deployments, updates, OSD and systems management solutions with the use of SCCM
- Develops, installs, recommends purchases, implementations and configuration of Microsoft technologies and Infrastructure systems
- Oversees the administration and operation of the physical server, telephony, networking and storage infrastructure, in data centers and offices geographically located around the country
- Researches, evaluates and recommends new technologies to meet business requirements and contributes to long-range planning for systems evolution
- Supports, upgrades and maintains media and broadcast related Microsoft servers and applications that are critical to the operation of the American Public Media Group automation and play to air systems in a 24x7x365 environment

SIS Systems Administrator I, Infinite Campus, Inc., Blaine, MN, 7/2012 – 12/2012

- Assists with the testing and deployment of internal operations tools; contributes to increased customer service and efficient product delivery
- Configures and installs a customer-purchased web application, and dependent software, to remote-access servers and maintains the internal system requirements for continued software delivery and use at the largest American-owned Student Information System provider
- Executes timely XML code changes and Apache Tomcat upgrades to ensure continued functionality of the web application during a continuous product development cycle
- Manages client database backup tasks through use of an internally-built tool; processes requested database restores and ensures the availability of client data
- Performs SQL server database management, including any necessary script modification and execution

IT Systems Specialist, Infinite Campus, Inc., 12/2010 – 10/2012

- Assisted with the assignment and upkeep of user security rights and mailing distribution groups in Active Directory
- Configured communications equipment and user/device profiles in the software-based callprocessing system utilized by the company (Cisco Unified CM)
- Identified and repaired network-related issues using a network access control appliance
- Performed installation, configuration, and maintenance of various hardware and software on both user workstations and data center servers
- Planned, designed, built, tested and deployed SCCM 2012 infrastructure corporate-wide;
 created and deployed software packages, SCEP definitions, and Windows updates
- Provided both live and remote-access technical support; repaired and maintained the software, hardware and network infrastructure used by the company's 400+ employees
- Served as the Help Desk team lead and managed the issue queue in the IT case system (JIRA)

EDUCATION

Web Development Immersive, General Assembly, LA, 3/2017

Associate of Applied Science, Computer Networking, Dunwoody College of Technology, Minneapolis, MN, 12/2010